Rabinowitch, Eugene I.; Papers ger075
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists, 1945-1973; 2
  - Administration, 1945-1972; 2.2
    The Administration files are arranged alphabetically by subject. They contain minutes, agenda, annual reports, bylaws, financial statements, grant applications, subscription lists, circulation reports, and promotional materials. The files document the day-to-day activities of the BAS and detail the organizational structure which supported the journal. Included in these files are minutes and papers dating from 1945 to 1949 of the Atomic Scientists of Chicago. This was the organization which initially sponsored publication of the Bulletin.
    - Annual Reports, 1956-1958 (Box 2 (2-Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists), Folder 54)
    - Atomic Scientists of Chicago, 1945 August-1949 (Box 2 (2-Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists), Folder 55)
    - Board of Directors, Minutes and Agenda, 1947 February-1970 December (Box 2 (2-Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists), Folder 56)
    - Bylaws, 1949 January-1969 December (Box 3 (2-Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists), Folder 1)
    - Circulation, 1946-June 1969; Undated (Box 3 (2-Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists), Folder 2)
    - Editorial Board, 1947 February-1970 March (Box 3 (2-Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists), Folder 3)
    - Financial Matters, 1946 April-1960 (Box 3 (2-Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists), Folder 4)
    - Financial Matters, 1961 January-1969 (Box 3 (2-Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists), Folder 5)
    - Financial Matters, 1970 February-1972 April; Undated (Box 3 (2-Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists), Folder 6)
    - Grants, 1949 January-1971 (Box 3 (2-Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists), Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous, 1946-1971; Undated (Box 3 (2-Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists), Folder 8)
    - Promotional Campaign, 1963 (Box 3 (2-Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists), Folder 9)
    - A Seven Year Program, 1960 (Box 3 (2-Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists), Folder 10)
  - Articles, 1947-1971; 2.3
    The Articles are arranged alphabetically by author's name. The files contain correspondence, memoranda, drafts of articles, galleys, reprints, resource material for articles, and clippings. The articles were submitted to Rabinowitch for publication in the BAS and may or may not have actually been printed. Articles which Rabinowitch himself may have written for the Bulletin are not included here but have been placed in Series 5 with his other writings.
    - Artsimovitch, L. A., "The Modern Physicist: Notes on Science and Its Role in Society", 1970 (Box 3 (2-Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists), Folder 11)
    - Baez, Albert V., 1964 February (Box 3 (2-Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists), Folder 12)
    - Born, Max, "Europe and Science", 1958 February (Box 3 (2-Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists), Folder 13)
    - Brown, Harrison, "How Vulnerable Are We-", Undated (Box 3 (2-Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists), Folder 14)
    - Clippings, 1947 April-1966 December; Undated (Box 3 (2-Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists), Folder 15)
    - Conrad, Thomas M., 1968 February-1969 March; Undated (Box 3 (2-Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists), Folder 16)
    - Cosic, Dobrica, "Toward an Intellectual Community", 1965 January (Box 3 (2-Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists), Folder 17)
    - Delbars, Yves, Russia's First Atomic Explosion, press release, 1949 October (Box 3 (2-Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists), Folder 18)
    - Drell, Sydney D., "University Programs in Science and Public Policy", Undated (Box 3 (2-Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists), Folder 19)
    - Emelyanov, V., "On the Threshold of Atomic Energetics", 1970 October; Undated (Box 3 (2-Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists), Folder 20)
    - Feld, Bernard T., 1968 December-1971 July (Box 3 (2-Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists), Folder 21)
    - Frank, J. D., "On Leading from Nuclear Strength - Some Sociopsychological Considerations", Undated (Box 3 (2-Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists), Folder 22)
    - Goudsmit, S. A.Brighter Than a Thousand Suns, book review, 1958 October (Box 3 (2-Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists), Folder 23)
    - Kowalski, Heinrich", Nuclear Slang and Nuclear Terminology", Undated (Box 3 (2-Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists), Folder 24)
    - Lapp, R. E., 1949 November; Undated (Box 3 (2-Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists), Folder 25)
    - Lowe, George E., "The Camelot Affair", 1965 December-1966 January; Undated (Box 3 (2-Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists), Folder 26)
    - Miller, Byron, Atomic Energy Regulation, book review, Undated (Box 3 (2-Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists), Folder 27)
    - Miscellaneous, 1962 April-1970 April; Undated (Box 3 (2-Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists), Folder 28)
    - Nemec, Frank A., "The Soviet Maritime Establishment", 1964 December (Box 3 (2-Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists), Folder 29)
    - Osgood, Charles E., "Escalation and De-Escalation as Political Strategies", 1966 February (Box 3 (2-Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists), Folder 30)
    - Schelling, Thomas C., Arms and Influence, Undated (Box 3 (2-Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists), Folder 31)
    - Scudder, Thayer "The Karbia Case: Manmade Lakes and Resource Development in Africa", 1965 December (Box 3 (2-Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists), Folder 32)
    - Semenov, N. N., "The Future of Mankind in the Atomic Age", Undated (Box 3 (2-Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists), Folder 33)
    - Shils, Edward, "Scientists and Their Society", Undated (Box 3 (2-Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists), Folder 34)
    - Simpson, Mary M., 1957 October-1959 January; Undated (Box 3 (2-Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists), Folder 35)
    - Silvert, K. H., "The Grand Politics of Development Assistance", Undated (Box 3 (2-Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists), Folder 36)
    - Snow, Joel A., "Science and the Human Condition", 1968 December-1969 January (Box 3 (2-Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists), Folder 37)
    - Sponsler, George C., "Technology for Taiwan", Undated (Box 3 (2-Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists), Folder 38)
    - Still, Joseph W., "Biology, Psychology, and Foreign Policy", 1960 January (Box 3 (2-Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists), Folder 39)
    - Teller, Edward, "Comments on the 'Draft of a World Constitution", 1948 April (Box 3 (2-Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists), Folder 40)
    - Varsavsky, Carlos M., "Development, Underdevelopment and Misdevelopment", Undated (Box 3 (2-Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists), Folder 41)
    - Warshauer, Albert D., "Key Information in the Medical and Social Sciences", 1970 August (Box 3 (2-Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists), Folder 42)
    - White, Gilbert F., "Vietnam: The Fourth Course", 1964 December (Box 3 (2-Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists), Folder 43)
    - Wilson, Jane, The Double Helix, book review, 1968 May (Box 3 (2-Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists), Folder 44)
    - Wood, Frederick B., "The Social Responsibility of Engineers and Scientists", 1959 March-1959 April (Box 3 (2-Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists), Folder 45)
- Pugwash Conferences on Science and World Affairs, 1957-1972; 3
  The Conferences on Science and World Affairs, otherwise known as Pugwash, "is a union of scientists who are concerned about the relations between science and society". Stated simply by Joseph Rotblat, secretary general of the movement, the aim of Pugwash is "to ensure that mankind will not destroy itself. Rabinowitch had an early influence in establishing the Pugwash Movement. In 1954 he opened discussions with Joseph Rotblat of Great Britain's Atomic Scientists' Association, which led to the 1955 International Conference on Science and Society. This conference endorsed the Russell-Einstein Manifesto which had been published shortly before. The Manifesto called for a conference of scientists to review the dangers of nuclear war and discuss means of achieving international understanding. This was fulfilled in the meeting of scientists in July 1957 at Pugwash, Nova Scotia. The name of the site became the name of the movement - Pugwash. The Pugwash Conferences on Science and World Affairs, 1957-1972, consist of a small, fragmentary amount of material dating primarily from the 1960s. The files are arranged in four categories-correspondence, conferences, symposia, and clippings. The conferences are arranged by date of meeting; the symposia are arranged alphabetically by title of meeting. Material within the files is arranged chronologically by year, month, and day. Partially dated items are placed at the end of the month or year; undated items are placed after dated material. Enclosures are placed after their letter of transmittal.
  Rabinowitch attended this first conference and was selected to serve on the Continuing Committee whose purpose was to organize future meetings. Rabinowitch remained a member of the Committee until just prior to his death in 1973. Throughout his life Rabinowitch was active in the Pugwash Movement, attending every conference and serving as president of the 1970 conference held at Fontana, Wisconsin. The files consist of incoming and outgoing correspondence, minutes, agenda, reports, financial statements, conference papers, participant lists, and clippings. The correspondence chiefly concerns planning for the various Pugwash conferences. Among the correspondents are Cyrus S. Eaton, who provided the financial backing of the early conferences; Joseph Rotblat, the first secretary general of Pugwash; and Bertrand Russell, who was one of the initiators of the Pugwash Movement. There are small amounts of material concerning eight of the international Pugwash conferences. Of interest among this material is a statement drafted by Rabinowitch for the 1962 conference in London.
  During Rabinowitch's lifetime the following conferences were held:
  First Conference: Pugwash, Nova Scotia, July 7-10, 1957.
  Second Conference: Lac Beauport, France, March 31 - April 11, 1958, "The Dangers of the Present Situation, and Ways and Means of Diminishing Them".
  Third Conference: Kitzbubel and Vienna, Austria, September 14-20, 1958, "Dangers of the Atomic Age and What Scientists Can Do About Them".
  Fourth Conference: Baden, Austria, June 25 - July 4, 1959, "Arms Control and World Security".
  Fifth Conference: Pugwash, Nova Scotia, August 24-29, 1959, "Biological and Chemical Warfare".
  Sixth Conference: Moscow, USSR, November 27 - December 5, 1960, "Disarmament and World Security".
  Seventh Conference: Stowe, Vermont, September 5-9, 1961, "International Cooperation in Pure and Applied Science".
  Eighth Conference: Stowe, Vermont, September 11-16, 1961, "Disarmament and World Security".
  Ninth Conference: Cambridge, England, August 25-30, 1962, "Problems of Disarmament and World Security".
  Tenth Conference: London, England, September 3-7, 1962, "Scientists and World Affairs".
  Eleventh Conference: Dubrovnik, Yugoslavia, September 20-25, 1963, "Current Problems of Disarmament and World Security".
  Twelfth Conference: Udaipur, India, January 27 - February 1, 1964, "Current Problems of Disarmament and World Security".
  Thirteenth Conference: Karlovy Vary, Czechoslovakia, September 13-19, 1964, "Disarmament and Peaceful Collaboration Among Nations".
  Fourteenth Conference: Venice, Italy, April 11-16, 1965, "International Cooperation for Science and Disarmament".
  Fifteenth Conference: Addis Ababa, Ethiopia, December 29, 1965 - January 3, 1966, "Science in Aid of Developing Countries".
  Sixteenth Conference: Sopot, Poland, September 11-16, 1966, "Disarmament and World Security, Especially in Europe".
  Seventeenth Conference: Ronneby, Sweden, September 3-198, 1967, "Scientists and World Affairs".
  Eighteenth Conference: Nice, France, September 11-16, 1968, "Current Problems of Peace, Security and Development".
  Nineteenth Conference: Sochi, USSR, October 22-2.7, 1969, "World Security, Disarmament and Development".
  Twentieth Conference: Fontana, Wisconsin, September 9-15, 1970, "Peace and International Cooperation: A Programme for the Seventies".
  Twenty-first Conference: Sinaia, Romania, August 26-31, 1971, "Problems of World Security, Environment and Development".
  - Correspondence, 1960 May-1972 June; Undated (Box 3 (3-Pugwash Conferences on Science and World Affairs), Folder 46)
  - First Conference, Pugwash, Nova Scotia, 1957 July (Box 3 (3-Pugwash Conferences on Science and World Affairs), Folder 47)
  - Tenth Conference, London, 1962 January-1962 May (Box 3 (3-Pugwash Conferences on Science and World Affairs), Folder 48)
  - Thirteenth Conference, Karlovy Vary, Czechoslovakia, 1964 September (Box 3 (3-Pugwash Conferences on Science and World Affairs), Folder 49)
  - Fifteenth Conference, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia, 1965 December-1966 January; Undated (Box 3 (3-Pugwash Conferences on Science and World Affairs), Folder 50)
  - Sixteenth Conference, Sopot, Poland, 1966 April-1966 September; Undated (Box 3 (3-Pugwash Conferences on Science and World Affairs), Folder 51)
  - Nineteenth Conference, Sochi, USSR, 1969 February-1971 January (Box 3 (3-Pugwash Conferences on Science and World Affairs), Folder 52)
  - Twentieth Conference, Lake Geneva (Fontana), Wisconsin, 1968 October-1970 October (Box 3 (3-Pugwash Conferences on Science and World Affairs), Folder 53)
  - Twenty-first Conference, Sinaia, Romania, 1971 August-1971 October (Box 3 (3-Pugwash Conferences on Science and World Affairs), Folder 54)
  - Symposia - Evolution o f Science and Technology in the Light of Basic World Problems, 1969 February-1969 March (Box 3 (3-Pugwash Conferences on Science and World Affairs), Folder 55)
  - Symposia - International Summer School on Disarmament and Arms Control, 1966 June-1969 May (Box 3 (3-Pugwash Conferences on Science and World Affairs), Folder 56)
  - Symposia - Science and Development Symposia, Stanford University, 1970 January-1972 June (Box 3 (3-Pugwash Conferences on Science and World Affairs), Folder 57)
  - Symposia - Social Aspects of Technological Change, 1970 October-1971 June (Box 3 (3-Pugwash Conferences on Science and World Affairs), Folder 58)
  - Symposia - Clippings, 1957 July-1969 October (Box 3 (3-Pugwash Conferences on Science and World Affairs), Folder 59)
- Conferences, 1959-1972; 4
  The Conferences, 1959-1972, files date primarily from 1966 to 1971. The files are arranged alphabetically by title of the conference. Items within the files are arranged chronologically by year, month, and day. Partially dated items are placed at the end of the month or year; undated items are placed after dated material. The files contain correspondence, reports, conference papers, programs, agenda, lecture notes, participant lists, receipts, vouchers, pamphlets, and leaflets. The files represent conferences, which Rabinowitch attended or presented a paper. There are also files concerning conferences to which Rabinowitch was invited but was unable to attend. A number of the conferences reflect Rabinowitch's interests in photosynthesis and photochemistry. Other conferences concern his work in international affairs, such as the Hiroshima Conference.
  - Bioastronautics and the Exploration of Space, Fourth International Symposium, 1968 June (Box 3 (4-Conferences), Folder 60)
  - Brown University Engineering Colloquia, 1967 January-1967 May (Box 3 (4-Conferences), Folder 61)
  - Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions, Planning Conference, 1966 May-1966 June (Box 3 (4-Conferences), Folder 62)
  - The Challenge of Building Peace, National Convocation, 1968 December-1971 October (Box 3 (4-Conferences), Folder 63)
  - Changing Human Relations, 1968 July (Box 3 (4-Conferences), Folder 64)
  - Colloque Photosynthèse, Undated (Box 3 (4-Conferences), Folder 65)
  - Colloquium on Science and Public Affairs, 1963 October-1963 December (Box 3 (4-Conferences), Folder 66)
  - Conference on World Tensions, Undated (Box 3 (4-Conferences), Folder 67)
  - European Biophysics Conference, 1970 September-1971 September (Box 3 (4-Conferences), Folder 68)
  - Evolution Conferences, 1960 May-1960 December (Box 3 (4-Conferences), Folder 69)
  - Evolution Conferences, 1960 December (Box 3 (4-Conferences), Folder 70)
  - The Future of American Society-Work and Leisure, SUNYA Academic Affairs Colloquium, 1967 April-1967 May (Box 4 (4-Conferences), Folder 1)
  - Future of Mankind and the Role of Christian Churches in a World of Science-Based Technology, 1972 January-1972 April (Box 4 (4-Conferences), Folder 2)
  - Galaxy Conference on Adult Education, 1969 March-1970 January (Box 4 (4-Conferences), Folder 3)
  - Gordon Research Conferences, 1962 May-1969 June (Box 4 (4-Conferences), Folder 4)
  - Hiroshima Conference, 1969-November 1970 (Box 4 (4-Conferences), Folder 5)
  - Hiroshima Conference, 1970 December-1971 March; Undated (Box 4 (4-Conferences), Folder 6)
  - Hiroshima 25 Years Later, American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1970 July-1971 February; Undated (Box 4 (4-Conferences), Folder 7)
  - Impact of Aerospace Science and Technology on Law and Government, 1968 July (Box 4 (4-Conferences), Folder 8)
  - International Congress of Photosynthesis Research, 1971 January-1971 June (Box 4 (4-Conferences), Folder 9)
  - International Future Research Conference, Kyoto, Japan, 1969 July-1969 November (Box 4 (4-Conferences), Folder 10)
  - Interreligious Understanding, Conference on, 1967 December-1968 January (Box 4 (4-Conferences), Folder 11)
  - Logic - Physical Reality History International Colloquium, 1966 May (Box 4 (4-Conferences), Folder 12)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology Centennial Conference on Science and Engineering, 1968 April (Box 4 (4-Conferences), Folder 13)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology March Fourth Work Stoppage, 1969 January-1969 October (Box 4 (4-Conferences), Folder 14)
  - Midwest Conference on Contemporary Soviet Problems, Northwestern University, 1960 January-1960 March; Undated (Box 4 (4-Conferences), Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous, 1959 November-1972 May; Undated (Box 4 (4-Conferences), Folder 16)
  - Nuclear Science Symposium, IEEE, 1971 January (Box 4 (4-Conferences), Folder 17)
  - Peru - United States Science Workshop, 1966 February-1966 April (Box 4 (4-Conferences), Folder 18)
  - Photochemistry in the Liquid and Solid States Symposium, 1959 March (Box 4 (4-Conferences), Folder 19)
  - Photosynthesis Bicentennial Symposium, National Academy of Sciences, 1970 August-1972 January (Box 4 (4-Conferences), Folder 20)
  - The Photosynthetic Unit, 1969 June-1970 October (Box 4 (4-Conferences), Folder 21)
  - Physique Theorique et Biologie, Conference Internationale, Versailles, 1966 December-1967 June (Box 4 (4-Conferences), Folder 22)
  - The Political Attitudes of Scientists, American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1969 April-1970 January (Box 4 (4-Conferences), Folder 23)
  - Primary Photochemistry of Photosynthesis, 1971 May-1971 November; Undated (Box 4 (4-Conferences), Folder 24)
  - Science and Technology in the Developing Countries Seminar, 1968 February-1968 May (Box 4 (4-Conferences), Folder 25)
  - Science and the Human Condition, University of Illinois, 1967 November-1967 December (Box 4 (4-Conferences), Folder 26)
  - Science and the Human Condition, 1968 January-1968 April; Undated (Box 4 (4-Conferences), Folder 27)
  - Science in Education and Public Life Symposium, 1966 November-1966 December (Box 4 (4-Conferences), Folder 28)
  - Science, Technology and Foreign Affairs Seminar, Foreign Service Institute, 1965 January-1965 February; Undated (Box 4 (4-Conferences), Folder 29)
  - Seminar with North American Scientists on Links with I Developing Countries, 1968 May (Box 4 (4-Conferences), Folder 30)
  - University of Edinburgh, Science Studies Unit Inaugural Seminar, 1966 November (Box 4 (4-Conferences), Folder 31)
  - Venezuelan Association for the Advancement of Science, Annual Conventions, 1967-March 1968 (Box 4 (4-Conferences), Folder 32)
  - World Assembly for Peace, Berlin, 1968 June (Box 4 (4-Conferences), Folder 33)
- Writings, 1923-1972; 5
  The Writings, 1923-1972, are organized in two parts Subseries A: Writings by Rabinowitch and Subseries B: Writings by Others. Material within the files is arranged chronologically by year, month, and day. Partially dated material is placed at the end of the month or year; undated items are placed after dated material.
  - Writings by Rabinowitch, 1923-1972; 5.1
    The Writings by Rabinowitch files date primarily from the 1960s. The files are arranged alphabetically by title or subject and contain correspondence, editorial letters, lecture notes, speeches, book reviews, royalty statements, typescript drafts, biographies, reprints, galley proofs, radio broadcast script, journals, and clippings. The files relate to Rabinowitch's books such as The Atomic Age, The Dawn of a New Age, Minutes to Midnight, and Photosynthesis. There are also files concerning Rabinowitch's numerous articles in scientific journals on the subject of photosynthesis. There are notes for and copies of speeches delivered by Rabinowitch. There are also files concerning articles and editorials which Rabinowitch prepared for publication in the Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists. In addition there are files relating to works translated by Rabinowitch from English to German or from German to Russian.
    - "Absorption Spectra of Uranyl Compounds in Solution", Argonne National Laboratory, 1953 December (Box 4 (5-Writings), Folder 34)
    - "Action Spectra of Fluorescence of Spinach Chloroplast Fractions Obtained by Solvent Extraction", 1968 August-1969 December (Box 4 (5-Writings), Folder 35)
    - "Albert Einstein", Undated (Box 4 (5-Writings), Folder 36)
    - Allison, Samuel King, Obituary BAS, 1965 September 10; Undated (Box 4 (5-Writings), Folder 37)
    - American Political Science Review, Book Reviews, 1969 October-1972 April (Box 4 (5-Writings), Folder 38)
    - American Scientists and Nuclear Weapons Policy, book review, 1962 May (Box 4 (5-Writings), Folder 39)
    - "Anti Hook", Undated (Box 4 (5-Writings), Folder 40)
    - "The Atom: Its Hazards and Benefits", Town Meeting, 1955 August (Box 4 (5-Writings), Folder 41)
    - The Atomic Age, Correspondence, 1962 April-1968 January; Undated (Box 4 (5-Writings), Folder 42)
    - The Atomic Ag e, Reviews, 1963 August-1965 January; Undated (Box 4 (5-Writings), Folder 43)
    - "The Atomic Age Doctrine: Common Efforts for Common Aims"BAS, 1960 September (Box 4 (5-Writings), Folder 44)
    - Atomic Bomb Public Opinion Poll, 1945 (Box 4 (5-Writings), Folder 45)
    - "The Atomic Pool", Undated (Box 4 (5-Writings), Folder 46)
    - "The Atomic Scientists Speak Up", Life, 1945 October; Undated (Box 4 (5-Writings), Folder 47)
    - "Atomic Spy Trials: Heretical Afterthoughts", Undated (Box 4 (5-Writings), Folder 48)
    - Atomnoia teoriia teoriia kvant: I. Atoundia teoriia by P. Kirchberger. Translated by Eugene Rabinowitch, 1923 (Box 4 (5-Writings), Folder 49)
    - "Before Hiroshima", 1946 May (Box 4 (5-Writings), Folder 50)
    - Biology Today, 1970 January-1972 April (Box 4 (5-Writings), Folder 51)
    - Biology Today, Undated (Box 4 (5-Writings), Folder 52)
    - Biophysics Lecture Notes, 1948-1949; Undated (Box 4 (5-Writings), Folder 53)
    - Bio Science Editorial, 1971 November (Box 4 (5-Writings), Folder 54)
    - Brighter Than a Thousand Suns, book review, Undated (Box 4 (5-Writings), Folder 55)
    - Chemistry of Uranium, 1944 September-1962 July (Box 4 (5-Writings), Folder 56)
    - "Chlorophyll, a in Anhydrous Ether in Various Drying Agents", 1965 May-1965 June; Undated (Box 4 (5-Writings), Folder 57)
    - "Compulsory Social Spending Instead of Taxation", 1971 May; Undated (Box 4 (5-Writings), Folder 58)
    - "Copping Out"Encounter, 1971 September (Box 4 (5-Writings), Folder 59)
    - "A Dangerous Lull", Undated (Box 4 (5-Writings), Folder 60)